# Anurudran Chandrasekaram . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent University of Toronto Scarborough graduate that completed my bachelor's degree in Computer Science specializing in Software Engineering. Currently, I am a Data/Software Engineer at Jarvis. Throughout my undergrad, I have learned a wide range of programming topics and languages. I was interested in topics such as algorithm design techniques, relational data modeling, and network security. I enjoy programming in Python, Java, and SQL by creating projects such as an Airbnb database or working on network security coding challenges. During my work terms in CIBC or at Ontario Public Services I have learned to work well in a fast-paced environment and gained experience working in Waterfall and Agile projects. I always appreciate working on various programming projects because it allows me to use the problem-solving and creative thinking skills that I excel in.

#### Skills

Proficient: Python, SQL(Postgres, MySQL), Java, Linux/Bash, Git

Competent: Agile/Scrum, Docker, Javascript, Network Security, HTML/CSS

Familiar: C, Haskell, SVN, Waterfall, Assembly language

# Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_AnurudranChandrasekaram

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Created a product that can get the host hardware information as well as all the host's usage information using bash scripts. Those scripts run every minute using crontab. Used PostgreSQL database to store the host's hardware and usage information so we can write SQL queries that can answer various business questions. This project was then dockerized for easy deployment.

## Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Created an app that can create, update and delete a tweet using the Twitter REST API. This app follows the DAO design pattern and uses Mockito and JUnit to create test cases for testing the app.
- JDBC App: Developed an application that uses the JDBC API that allows you to create a connection between Java code and PostgreSQL database. It uses the Create, Read, Update and Delete operations using the DAO design patterns.
- Grep App: Created an app that mimics the Linux grep command that takes a directory or file and traverses each file and line in each of those files to find a pattern that matches the regex expression. This app was written using Java and Stream APIs for efficient processing of large files and improving code simplicity. This project used Maven to install dependencies and dockerized for easy deployment.

## Highlighted Projects

**AirBnb Database**: Created an Airbnb Database using MySQL and Java. This application allows users to create an account as a host or renter and be able to host or rent a listing for certain days. Used relational data model to create a database design that allows the tables to be Boyce-Codd normal form.

Matplotlib FOSS feature: Contributed to a Matplotlib issue by extending a feature that can toggle the visibility of subplots on a graph through the legend handler. This project was worked with a group of 5 people using a Waterfall project methodology. The tools used were GitHub, python, and pytest to create and test the feature.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2022-present): Learning various programming languages such as Python, SQL, and Java and tools such as GitHub, Notion, Docker, and Maven by completing various projects such as the Cluster Monitor project or Java Twitter app. Also participated and lead an Agile/Scrum environment to complete the tasks and projects efficiently.

Jr Software Engineer Co-op, Ontario Public Service (September 2020 - April 2021): Developed test scripts using Java and Selenium to automate the webpages onto different web browsers to test the functionality of the website and used Git for the deployment of our code. Researched and developed new ways in doing load testing to ensure the websites can handle traffic overload and not crash.

Web Developer Co-op, Public Services and Procurement Canada (September 2019 - December 2019): Worked in a Waterfall style project management using Jira with a group of 6 co-workers to deliver the annual financial activities made by the country viewed by millions. Communicated effectively with clients by producing clarity and depth responses to significantly reduce turnaround back and forth communication.

Senior QA Specialist Co-op, CIBC Digital (January 2019 - April 2019): Used Adobe Experience Manager and eBanking platform to test changes made on the CIBC and Simplii website that is viewed by millions. Coordinated with team members through email and Jira to efficiently and effectively test, send changes, publish to production, and retest in production. Effectively tested new pages and variety of change requests varying from 5-50 changes to reduce reopening issues daily.

### Education

University of Toronto Scarborough (2016-2021), Honours Bachelor of Sciences, Computer Science specializing in Software Engineering

#### Miscellaneous

- Basketball and Ultimate Frisbee player
- Competitive gaming
- Working out